<content type="article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/greenslade/2009/mar/02/1" gdn-url="http://openapi.guardian.co.uk:8300/gdn-api/content/343339413">
  <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
  <headline>What the commentators say today...</headline>
  <byline>Roy Greenslade</byline>
  <section-name>Media</section-name>
  <trail-text> In association with media analysis firm Editorial Intelligence </trail-text>
  <link-text>What the commentators say today...</link-text>
  <publication-date>2009-03-03T00:00:00</publication-date>
  <tagged-with>
    <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://openapi.guardian.co.uk:8300/gdn-api/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article"/>
    <tag name="Blogposts" type="tone" filter="/global/blogpost" gdn-url="http://openapi.guardian.co.uk:8300/gdn-api/search?filter=/global/blogpost" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/blogpost"/>
    <tag name="Roy Greenslade" type="contributor" filter="/global/roygreenslade" gdn-url="http://openapi.guardian.co.uk:8300/gdn-api/search?filter=/global/roygreenslade" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/roygreenslade"/>
    <tag name="Greenslade" type="blog" filter="/media/greenslade" gdn-url="http://openapi.guardian.co.uk:8300/gdn-api/search?filter=/media/greenslade" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/greenslade"/>
    <tag name="Media" type="keyword" filter="/media" gdn-url="http://openapi.guardian.co.uk:8300/gdn-api/search?filter=/media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media"/>
  </tagged-with>
  <type-specific class="article">
    <body> In association with media analysis firm Editorial Intelligence  SIR FRED&apos;S PENSION: The Independent&apos;s Dominic Lawson says Sir Fred Goodwin is perfectly cast for the role of villain. It need not have come to this farcical pass, had the government handled its negotiations with a little more attention to detail. The Daily Mail&apos;s Richard Littlejohn notes that after finding that the government cannot legally strip Goodwin of his £693,000-a-year pension, Harriet Harman is pinning her hopes on the &apos;court of public opinion&apos;. In most other circumstances the government seemingly fights tooth and nail not to give in to public opinion. The Sun&apos;s Fergus Shanahan says there are a hundred things that Labour has done that deeply offend the court of public opinion. But it&apos;s the court of law that counts. The Daily Telegraph&apos;s Boris Johnson writes that he never thought anyone could have any sympathy for Goodwin, not at least until Harriet Harman took to the airwaves. Instead of pointing public rage towards a sober examination of what has gone wrong with pay scales during the last 20 years, writes Polly Toynbee in The Guardian, the leaders of the hue and cry have swung round to sink their teeth into the usual scapegoat - the public sector. In The Times, Tom Winsor, former rail regulator, says the implications of what ministers may do to punish Goodwin could inflict enormous harm on the British economy.  BROWN AND OBAMA: Today&apos;s meeting between Gordon Brown and Barack Obama in Washington is set against the backdrop of the gravest global crisis since 1945. The Daily Mail&apos;s Max Hastings believes the crisis is not simply about money, but the fact that it has threatened the stability and political fabric of entire societies. The Independent&apos;s Steve Richards argues that Obama has not invited Brown to Washington as an act of charity. Both recognise that the current crisis requires hyperactivity from governments and a new regulatory framework for banks that can be applied globally. In The Times, Ann Treneman says the prime minister launched his historic trip to America with a pre-tour interview on talkSPORT radio. It isn&apos;t often that we hear Brown so live and unplugged, and slightly unhinged. Rachel Sylvester says the danger for Brown on his American visit is that he risks being seen as grandstanding while Britons are losing their jobs and homes. Sir Christopher Meyer, former British ambassador to Washington, says even if the &apos;special relationship&apos; is alive and well, it does not mean that we shall be more important to the US than France or Germany. There is no harm in Brown&apos;s message during his US visit that Britain has a special place in the affections of the US, says Philip Stephens in The FT, but the sentimentality about shared history, sacrifices and values lies largely on the side of the visitors.  ECONOMY: The crisis in central and eastern Europe has been triggered by the world&apos;s financial turmoil, says Bronwen Maddox in The Times. In the Daily Express, Patrick O&apos;Flynn says that as unemployment soars, even the most smug British political class should realise the folly in throwing open our jobs market and welfare state to citizens of eastern Europe. </body>
  </type-specific>
</content>
